<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Steven Deobald</title>
    <link>https://www.deobald.ca/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Steven Deobald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.deobald.ca/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I am looking for work. (Taylor&#39;s Version)</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2025-01-01-i-am-looking-for-work-taylors-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2025-01-01-i-am-looking-for-work-taylors-version/</guid>
      <description>After 13 years of entrepreneurship, running businesses like Nilenso (India&amp;rsquo;s first worker-owned tech company) and Endatabas (earth&amp;rsquo;s first immutable HTAP SQL database), I&amp;rsquo;m looking for full-time employment. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed starting unique companies from scratch and taking them as far as I can, but now I want to help grow something larger than I could build myself.&#xA;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know me: I&amp;rsquo;m Steven, an engineering manager and developer from Canada. I have 15+ years of experience building and growing technology teams, while ensuring they build the right product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimistic Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2024-12-09-optimistic-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2024-12-09-optimistic-computing/</guid>
      <description>I recently made two new friends: Abhinav Omprakash and Dawn Walker. Abhinav said I&amp;rsquo;m an optimist and I should write about it. Dawn said I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to coin any new terms. I should know better, but this essay follows Abhinav&amp;rsquo;s recommendation &amp;mdash; and credits Dawn, in the very likely event I should have followed her advice instead.&#xA;I have been alive for approximately four decades. Each of those decades was witness to its own fun brand of computering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steve Yegge, You Are Half Right (Part Two: Software Ethics)</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-01-01-steve-yegge-you-are-half-right-part-two-software-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-01-01-steve-yegge-you-are-half-right-part-two-software-ethics/</guid>
      <description>In 21 Lessons for the 21st Century, Yuval Noah Harari repeatedly emphasizes the need for society to apply critical thinking to the future of software, algorithms, and artificial intelligence. Harari is one of the more forward-thinking philosophers when it comes to disruptive technology and 21 Lessons lucidly collects the requirements for our species&amp;rsquo; future: our new tools must sustainably respect future arcs of aggregate data use and they must do so globally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steve Yegge, You Are Half Right (Part One: An Ethical Void)</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2018-12-25-steve-yegge-you-are-half-right-part-one-an-ethical-void/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2018-12-25-steve-yegge-you-are-half-right-part-one-an-ethical-void/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer and Full Disclosure: I began writing this article in July, during my last week at nilenso. Go-Jek is a client of nilenso&amp;rsquo;s. My views represent neither company.&#xA;I just re-read Steve Yegge&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Why I left Google to join Grab&amp;rdquo; article. My heart is pumping. I&amp;rsquo;m excited. Just not in the way he intended.&#xA;You may have forgotten about Yegge&amp;rsquo;s article between the beginning and end of 2018 so feel free to go back and refresh your memory.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
