<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>off-grid on Steven Deobald</title>
    <link>https://www.deobald.ca/tags/off-grid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in off-grid on Steven Deobald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.deobald.ca/tags/off-grid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hacker Villages</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-11-20-hacker-villages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-11-20-hacker-villages/</guid>
      <description>The inevitable advent of जादूगरों का गाँव.
&amp;ldquo;Land in Canada costs how much?&amp;rdquo; Ragul queries me a second time. His eyes are wide and I can tell he&amp;rsquo;s asking me to confirm the cost of property in Eastern Canada because half of him doesn&amp;rsquo;t believe it.
&amp;ldquo;Yeah, I know,&amp;rdquo; I say, &amp;ldquo;$23,000 CAD for 20–30 acres is&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I pull out my phone and start punching the forex conversion into the search box but he gives me the answer off the top of his head before I can finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Spaces</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-03-01-silent-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-03-01-silent-spaces/</guid>
      <description>How often do we experience real silence?
Universal Spaces was written out of necessity. There is nothing profound about the idea of universal spaces &amp;mdash; spaces without any form of exceptional availability &amp;mdash; but no preexisting terminology satisfies the requirement of defining spaces only in terms of that quality. Universal spaces require an identity, something we can point to when we presuppose them as a superset of Silent Spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Spaces</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-02-05-universal-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-02-05-universal-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we visited Chennai&amp;rsquo;s Theosophical Society. Prior to this visit I knew little of Theosophy and nothing about the space. The Society is staggering in size. Bountiful gardens spread across 260 acres. Although it is dwarfed by large city parks like Central Park (850 acres) in New York and Stanley Park (1000 acres) in Vancouver, the Theosophical Society Gardens have an even more surprising quality: they are privately owned.
Think what we might about the Society&amp;rsquo;s belief systems, what became clear on our journey back home from an hour of meditation in the gardens was that they constitute an example of an idea Siggu has tossed around for a while: Universal Spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Has A Three-Body Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-02-01-india-has-a-three-body-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-02-01-india-has-a-three-body-problem/</guid>
      <description>When I moved to Bangalore six years ago, I had no interest in India&amp;rsquo;s garbage management problem. I moved here to build a software company, not to muck about with garbage bins. But every time I would fly between the subcontinent and the Americas, I would find relief on my home continent and exhaustion on my continent of immigration. Living in a giant garbage heap is mentally taxing. Every moment spent outdoors is either an angsty mental rundown of how I might help, complete with acute feelings of powerlessness, or searching for someone to blame (my brain&amp;rsquo;s lazy personal favourite is a generic and completely unhelpful &amp;ldquo;the middle class&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
