<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental Health on Steven Deobald</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental Health on Steven Deobald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compassion For Donald</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2019-08-28-compassion-for-donald/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2019-08-28-compassion-for-donald/</guid>
      <description>The 2019 Canadian federal election is over. I doubt anyone feels very good about it. Not because a minority government threatens to immobilize the Canadian government. I mean, there is that. But the suffocating air of this election was far less tangible, far less quantifiable, than counted ballots. The outmoded left-right political spectrum is gasping for breath through a death rattle and, for those of us who plan to be here on the far side, it&amp;rsquo;s disgusting to watch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silent Spaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2019-03-01-silent-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2019-03-01-silent-spaces/</guid>
      <description>How often do we experience real silence?&#xA;Universal Spaces was written out of necessity. There is nothing profound about the idea of universal spaces &amp;mdash; spaces without any form of exceptional availability &amp;mdash; but no preexisting terminology satisfies the requirement of defining spaces only in terms of that quality. Universal spaces require an identity, something we can point to when we presuppose them as a superset of Silent Spaces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal Spaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/2019-02-05-universal-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/2019-02-05-universal-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we visited Chennai&amp;rsquo;s Theosophical Society. Prior to this visit I knew little of Theosophy and nothing about the space. The Society is staggering in size. Bountiful gardens spread across 260 acres. Although it is dwarfed by large city parks like Central Park (850 acres) in New York and Stanley Park (1000 acres) in Vancouver, the Theosophical Society Gardens have an even more surprising quality: they are privately owned.&#xA;Think what we might about the Society&amp;rsquo;s belief systems, what became clear on our journey back home from an hour of meditation in the gardens was that they constitute an example of an idea Siggu has tossed around for a while: Universal Spaces.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
