<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>drugs on Steven Deobald</title>
    <link>https://www.deobald.ca/tags/drugs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in drugs on Steven Deobald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.deobald.ca/tags/drugs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does Smoking Marijuana Harm Your Meditation Practice?</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-01-11-does-smoking-marijuana-harm-your-meditation-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2019-01-11-does-smoking-marijuana-harm-your-meditation-practice/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: Yes, it does.
A friend with very little drug experience recently asked me if smoking (or eating) marijuana would harm her nascent meditation practice. She had a few follow-up questions, one of which was &amp;ldquo;have you ever written about this?&amp;rdquo; which caused me to turn our conversation into this essay.
First off, on the broad topic of drugs and meditation, I have written about my experiences and categorized the options once before in Drugs, Meditation, Warnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drugs, Meditation, Warnings</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2015-01-01-drugs-meditation-warnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2015-01-01-drugs-meditation-warnings/</guid>
      <description>I recently returned to work from my second 10-day Vipassana course. After such a course, friends are always curious about the experience. Because Vipassana meditation courses are largely indescribable, the conversation often drifts to one&amp;rsquo;s journey toward Vipassana, and the journey toward meditation in general. For me, this journey has been a mixture of friendships, literature, and drugs. Drugs can be seen as a stepping-stone to my current meditation practice because a few drugs have similar insightful (informational) qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
