<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Steven Deobald</title>
    <link>https://www.deobald.ca/categories/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Steven Deobald</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.deobald.ca/categories/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LocalFirst: You Keep Using That Word</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2026-01-01-localfirst-you-keep-using-that-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2026-01-01-localfirst-you-keep-using-that-word/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following the local-first scene over the past few years, you already know a good definition for the term &amp;ldquo;local-first&amp;rdquo; is hard to pin down.&#xA;Part of the reason is that most people write software for money &amp;hellip; and true local-first software is harder to capitalize. &amp;ldquo;Local-first&amp;rdquo; is a direct attack on vendor lock-in of all forms: data, formats, protocols, apps, services, and even environments. But the fact your employer can&amp;rsquo;t exploit this technology with a new revenue model (yet) is a minor problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Wave (Commercial) Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2024-08-13-third-wave-commercial-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deobald.ca/essays/2024-08-13-third-wave-commercial-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Commercial Open Source Software (COSS) is an only-loosely-agreed-upon term for businesses built upon selling open source products. COSS has seen two significant waves pass, with a third now emerging. The head of each wave lasts approximately a decade. The tail of each wave extends into the future indefinitely. Each wave subsumes all previous waves.&#xA;The first wave was characterized by shrinkwrapping and commercial support. Peaking in the mid-1990s, Red Hat was the poster-child of selling support for software written by other people.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
